

ISHARA
DISSANAYAKE
ASSOCIATE DATA SCIENTIST

**EXPERIENCE** 

2022 - PRESENT ASSOCIATE DATA

APR SCIENTIST

ShoutOUT AI (Part-time)

**2021 - 2022 DATA SCIENCE** SEP MAR **INTERN** 

ShoutOUT AI

(Full-time 06 Months)

**AWARDS** 

2022 DEAN'S LIST AWARD MAY

3rd Year 2nd Semester, SLIIT

2021 DEAN'S LIST AWARD

2nd Year 1st Semester, SLIIT

2020 DEAN'S LIST AWARD

1st Year 2nd Semester, SLIIT

2020 DEAN'S LIST AWARD

1st Year 1st Semester, SLIIT

**CERTIFICATIONS** 

2021 PCAP - PROGRAMMING
MAY ESSENTIALS IN PYTHON

Cisco

2021 INTRODUCTION TO IOT

JUN Cisco [Verify]

CONTACT

Primary: 0702090885 Secondary: 0718184147

thisisisharadissanayake@gmail.com

n linkedin.com/in/isharadissanayake

github.com/thisisishara

## **PROFILE**

An associate data scientist (AI & NLP) and a data science undergraduate with remarkable academic performance. Keen on learning new technologies related to data science, AI, ML, software development, and computer security. Focused on contributing to projects that make a better social impact while being a valuable asset to the organization through acquiring experience and constantly enhancing my skill set.

# **EDUCATION**

2018 - 2022 BSc (HONS) INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

DEC DEC SPECIALIZING IN DATA SCIENCE

SLIIT, Malabe, Sri Lanka

CGPA: 3.81

2015 GCE ADVANCED LEVEL

AUG Physical Science Stream

Sir John Kothalawala Collage, Kurunegala, Sri Lanka Subjects Taken: IT, Mathematics, and Physics

**PROJECTS** 

2022 Kolloqe: CODELESS BILINGUAL SaaS CONVERSATIONAL AI DEVELOPMENT PLATFORM (Undergraduate Research - NLP)

Python, React, MongoDB, Docker, Azure, NGINX [GitHub] [Live Demo]

2021 STARBUCKS DATA WAREHOUSE & BI SOLUTION

MAY ETL, SSIS, SSAS, SSRS, SSDT, Data Warehousing & BI, EXCEL

DASHBOARD, SQL Server 2019 [GitHub]

2021 GadgetBadget: A RESTful WEB SERVICES PROJECT

MAY Java, JAX-RS, Jersey, MySQL, Servlets, JS, jQuery, AJAX, JWT

Authentication, Microservices [GitHub]

2020 POCKET UNI MOBILE APP

OCT Android, Java, Firebase, SQL Lite, In-App Reminders [GitHub]

# **SKILLS**

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python • Machine Learning • Data Mining • NLP • Numpy • Pandas • Flask PowerBI • Apache Airflow • SQL • MongoDB Firebase • RASA Open-Source Data Warehousing & ETL • Java • JSP • APIs • Microservices Android Studio JS • React JS • C#.NET • AJAX • Docker • AWS • Linux • GIT

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

Collaborative • Inquisitive • Problem-Solving • Fluent in English Communication Skills • Critical Thinking

## REFERENCES

SLIIT, Malabe Campus

lumini.w@sliit.lk

0778144720

Ms. Lumini Wickramasinghe Ms. Shammi Hewamadduma

Assistant Lecturer Information Security Engineer Faculty of Computing Sri Lanka CERTICC

on Edilika GERTIOO

shammishara@gmail.com

0711516852 0765258406